Robert Porter Patterson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1909-1952 (Box 1-49)
  - General, 1945-1947 (Box 18-23)
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Adams, Jane S.
    - Addes, George F.
    - Adler, Julius O.
    - Allen, Robert S.
    - Allen, Terry
    - Alsop, Joseph
    - Amberg, Julius H.
    - Anderson, Troyer S.
    - Andrews, W. G.
    - Appointments consummated
    - Army-Navy Club, Washington, D.C.
    - Austin, Warren
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Baruch, Bernard
    - Baxter, James P.
    - Bellamy, Paul
    - Bennett, Kenneth
    - Berenson, Lawrence
    - Birthday greetings
    - Blai, Boris
    - Bliss, Robert
    - Bowles, E. L.
    - Boy Scouts of America
    - Breed, William C.
    - Brown, Perry C.
    - Burlingham, C. C.
    - Bullitt, William C.
    - Bush, Vannevar
    - Butler, Nicholas M.
    - Byrnes, James F.
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Cabinet meetings
    - Callahan, Sophy
    - Carlisle Barracks, Army Information School, Carlisle, Pa.
    - Chicago, Ill.
    - Churchill, Winston
    - Clark, Grenville
    - Clark, Mark W.
    - Clay, Lucius D.
    - Compton, Karl
    - Cutler, Robert
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Davis, Forrest
    - Derby, H. L.
    - Deremer, Earl D.
    - Dewey, Bradley
    - Dorr, Goldthwaite
    - Draper, William H.
    - Dulles, Allen
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Eads, Aubrey L.
    - Economics
    - Education manual
    - Edwards, Leroy M.
    - Emmerich, Herbert
    - Entertainment
    - Erie Basin Metal Products
    - Evarts, William M.
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Freeman, Douglas W.
    - Frye, William
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Gardner General Hospital, Chicago, Ill.
    - Gaud, William S.
    - Ginsberg, David
    - Goodyear, A. C.
    - Goodyear, Philip
    - Gordon, Malcolm K.
    - Graham, Philip
    - Greenbaum, Edward S.
    - Griswold, Dwight
    - Griffis, Stanton
    - "H" miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Hand, Learned
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Haskell, William N.
    - Haven's Relief Fund Society
    - Hemphill, Edward S.
    - Hodge, John R.
    - Hoffman, William W.
    - Holt, Palmer
    - Hook, Charles R.
    - Hoopes, Maurice
    - Hoover, Herbert
    - Housing
    - Hoyt, Palmer
    - Hyde, Donald H.
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Johnson, Kenneth
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.
    - Joint Army-Navy Committee
    - Jones, Jesse H.
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Klein, Julius
    - Knopf, Alfred A.
    - Knowlson, James S.
    - Knudsen, William S.
    - Krock, Arthur
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Leadership School
    - Legislation
    - Letore, Fernando
    - Lewis, Lloyd
    - Lodwick, Albert I.
    - Ludwig, Emil
    - "Mc" miscellaneous
    - McCabe, Thomas
    - McCloy, John
    - McIntyre, James
    - McNutt, Paul
    - "M" miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - Marbury, William
    - Marshall, George
    - Mayer, Arthur
    - Meigs, Merrill C.
    - Memberships
    - Mexico
    - Middleton, E. Willoughby
    - Minton, Sherman
    - Morganthau, Henry (1891-1967)
    - Murray, Robert H.
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Nation
    - National Guard Associations
    - Nelson, Donald
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - O'Brien, John P.
    - Ondi case
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Page, Arthur W.
    - Parker, Frank
    - Patterson, Robert Porter
    - Patton, George S. (1885-1945)
    - Paul, Randolph
    - Pell, Herbert
    - Practicing Law Institute
    - Press conferences
    - Price, Lewis
    - "Q" miscellaneous (Box 22)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Reeder, Russell P.
    - Reelfoot Lake, Tenn.
    - Renegotiations of contracts
    - Rental of property, (2 folders)
    - Rodey, Pearce C.
    - Rosenberg, Anna M.
    - Royall, Kenneth C.
    - Rukeyser, Merryle S.
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Sachs, Alexander
    - Saltonstall, Leverett
    - Sears, Charles B.
    - Seversky, Alexander P. de
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
    - Snow, Conrad E.
    - Spellman, Francis Joseph, Cardinal
    - Steed, Mother
    - Stimson, Henry L.
    - Stryker, Lloyd P.
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard
    - Symington, W. Stuart
    - "T" miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Tobin, Ralph C.
    - Trips Overseas, (6 folders)
    - Tydings, Millard E.
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Union College, Schenectady, N.Y.
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Voorhees, Tracey
    - "W" miscellaneous
    - War Council meetings
    - War Department
    - Webb, Vanderbilt
    - West Point
    - Wilkins, Raymond S.
    - Wood, Eric F.
    - Wood, R. E.
    - Woodson, B. N.
    - "X-Z" miscellaneous
  - Bound, 1940-1947 (Box 24-27)
    Letters sent, memoranda, reports, and a manuscript.
    Arranged chronologically in nine volumes.
    - 1940-1942, (2 vols.) (Box 24)
    - 1943-1944, (2 vols.) (Box 25)
    - 1945-1946, (2 vols.) (Box 26)
    - 1947 (Box 27)
  - General, 1947-1952 (Box 28-48)
    Arranged alphabetically by subject and therein chronologically
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box 28)
    - American Association for the United Nations
    - American Bar Association, (2 folders)
    - American Bar Association Commission on Organized Crime
      - July 1950-July 1951, (8 folders)
      - Aug. 1951-Jan. 1952, (4 folders) (Box 29)
    - American Committee on United Europe
    - Atlantic Union Committee, (5 folders)
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Bernstein, Philip S.
    - "C" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    - Carey, William F.
    - Cellar, Emanuel
    - Century Association
    - Cherney, William L.
    - Clark, Bennett C.
    - Clark, Mark W.
    - Clay, Lucius D.
    - Clayton, William L.
    - Clinchy, Everett L.
    - Collins, J. Lawton
    - Colt, S. Sloan
    - Commission on the Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government, (4 folders)
    - Conant, James B.
    - Congratulatory letters (Box 31)
      - 1945
        - A-H
        - I-Z (Box 32)
      - 1947 (Box 33)
        - July
        - October (Box 34)
    - Connery, Robert H. (Box 35)
    - Cooper, Irving B.
    - Cosmopolitan
    - Coudert, Frederic R.
    - Cox, Oscar
    - "D" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Daniels, Joseph J.
    - Davenport, John
    - Davis, Arch
    - Davis, Elmer E.
    - De Rachet, Nicholas G.
    - Desmond, Thomas C.
    - Dewey, Bradley
    - Dewey, Thomas E.
    - Donohoe, John P.
    - Donovan, William J.
    - Doolittle, James H.
    - Dougherty, Richard H.
    - Douglas, Paul H.
    - Draper, William H.
    - Drum, Hugh H.
    - Dubinsky, David
    - Dulles, Allen
    - "E" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Eberstradt, F.
    - Edwards, Leroy M.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - Ellis, Emil K. (Box 36)
    - Evarts, William M.
    - "F" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Farley, James A.
    - Fitzpatrick, Paul E.
    - Forrestal, James
    - Franklin, George S., Sr.
    - Freedom House, (6 folders)
    - Frye, William
    - "G" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Galdston, Iago
    - Garrigues, Mr. and Mrs. Paul
    - Gennovario, Pasque
    - Glancy, Alfred R.
    - Goldsmith, Arthur J. (Box 37)
    - Goldstein, Nathaniel
    - Goldwyn, Samuel S.
    - Goodrich, Herbert F.
    - Gray, Gordon
    - Green, Norvin H.
    - Greenbaum, Edward S.
    - Greene, Joseph I.
    - Greenman, Frederick D.
    - Gruening, Ernest
    - "H" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Hand, Learned
    - Harvard Club of the City of New York, N.Y.
    - Harvard Law School Association, (3 folders)
    - Harvard Law School Fund
    - Harvey, J. Darrell
    - Haven's Relief Fund Society
    - Haviland, John C.
    - Hennock, Frieda B.
    - Henry, M. W.
    - Hertz, John
    - Hirsch, Maurice
    - Hiss, Alger
    - Hofstra College, Hempstead, N.Y.
    - Hook, Charles R.
    - Hoopes, Maurice
    - Hoover, Herbert
    - Howard, Roy (Box 38)
    - Hoyt, Palmer
    - Hyde, Donald R.
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - International Business Machines Corp.
    - International Business Machines Country Club, Poughkeepsie, N.Y.
    - Isaccs, Stanley M.
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Javits, Jacob K.
    - Jessup, Philip C.
    - Johnson, Kenneth
    - Johnson, Louis Arthur
    - Jones, Catesby L.
    - Jones, Jesse H.
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kaufman, Irving R.
    - Kefauver, Estes
    - Klausner, Joseph A.
    - Klein, Julius, (2 folders)
    - Knox, John
    - Kohlberg, Alfred
    - Kupfer, Milton P.
    - "L" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Laoa-Moscarski, V.
    - La Porte, Cloyd
    - Lasker, Albert Davis
    - Le Boutillier, Alice
    - Legal Aid Society
    - Lilienthal, David Eli
    - Livingston, George
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1902-1985)
    - Long Island Rail Road Commission, (11 folders); (10 folders) (Box 40)
    - Lovett, Robert A.
    - Lubin, Isadore
    - "Mc" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - McAllister, Dorothy
    - MacArthur, Douglas (Box 41)
    - McCabe, Thomas B.
    - McCarran, Patton Pat
    - McCook, Philip J.
    - McCloy, John J.
    - McGrath, J. Howard
    - McKay, Josephine
    - McKee, Frederick C.
    - McLaughlin, Chester B.
    - McMahon, Brien
    - "M" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Mackrell, John J.
    - Marbury, William
    - Marcus, J. Anthony
    - Marshall, George C.
    - Marshall Plan, (4 folders)
    - Medina, Harold R. (Box 42)
    - Meigs, Merrill C.
    - Middleton, Bissell J.
    - Middleton, E. Willoughby
    - Middleton, Thomas H.
    - Migone, Raul C.
    - Military justice, (5 folders)
    - Moore, Hugh
    - Morgenthau, Henry (1891-1967)
    - Morganthau, Robert M.
    - Moses, Robert
    - Moskovit, Harold R.
    - Murphy, Vincent P.
    - "N" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - National Fund for Medical Education
    - Newman, James R.
    - New York County Lawyers Association
    - New York Times
    - New York University School of Law, New York, N.Y.
    - Nizer, Louis
    - "O" miscellaneous (Box 43)
    - O'Brien, John L.
    - O'Connor, Basil
    - Odum, Howard W.
    - O'Dwyer, William
    - Orgill, Edmund
    - "P" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Pace, Frank, Jr.
    - Panuch, J. Anthony
    - Parkman, Henry
    - Parks, F. L.
    - Permanent Court of Arbitration
    - Petersen, Howard C.
    - Phillips, John C.
    - Phillips, Nathaniel
    - Porter, Charles C.
    - Practicing Law Institute, New York, N.Y.
    - Proskauer, Joseph M.
    - "Q" miscellaneous
    - "R" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 44)
    - Radcliffe, George L.
    - Rayburn, Sam
    - Real Estate Board of New York City, New York, N.Y.
    - Regrets of invitations
    - Remington, Thomas H.
    - Rental of apartment
    - Reynolds, Richard H.
    - Ringel, William E.
    - Roberts, George
    - Roberts, Owen J.
    - Rodman, T. Clifford
    - Roelker, Alfred
    - Roosevelt, Belle
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor
    - Roosevelt Memorial Foundation, (2 folders)
    - Root, Oren
    - Rosenberg, Anna M. (Box 45)
    - Rosenberg, James N.
    - Royall, Kenneth C.
    - "S" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Sachs, Alexander
    - Sargent, W. L.
    - Scherbak, H.
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M.
    - Schram, Emil
    - Schroder Banking Corp.
    - Seversky, Alexander P. de, (2 folders)
    - Seymour, Whitney N.
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
    - Silverstein, Samuel
    - Skouras, Spyros
    - Smedley, Frederic C.
    - Smith, H. Alexander
    - Smith, Reginald H. (Box 46)
    - Somervell, Brehon
    - Spellman, Francis Joseph, Cardinal
    - Spence, Kenneth M.
    - Spivak, Lawrence
    - Steelman, John R.
    - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur
    - Stein, Harold
    - Stickles, Lester D.
    - Stimson, Henry L.
    - Streit, Clarence K.
    - Stryker, Lloyd P.
    - Sturges, Wesley A.
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, (2 folders)
    - "T" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Tarshes, Milton
    - Taylor, C. W., Jr.
    - Thatcher, Archibald G.
    - Thomason, R. Ewing
    - Truman, Harry S.
    - Tweed, Harrison
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Union College, Schenectady, N.Y., (3 folders)
    - United States Committee for a United Nations Genocide Convention, (12 folders) (Box 47)
    - Universal military training
    - "V" miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Vanderbilt, Arthur T.
    - Voorhees, Tracey
    - "W" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Ward, Orlando
    - Wardwell, Allen
    - Washington Post
    - Waters, John K.
    - Watson, Mark S.
    - Watson, Thomas J., (2 folders)
    - White, Walter
    - Wickersham, Cornelius W.
    - Wiener, Frederick B.
    - Williams, Paul W.
    - Williston, Arthur L.
    - Wilson, Charles E.
    - Witsell, Edward F.
    - Wood, Chester
    - Woods, Helen
    - Wooster School, Danbury, Conn.
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous, May-Sept. 1948 (Box 49)
- Legal File, 1913-1940 (Box 50-90)
  Briefs, notes, correspondence concerning legal cases, reports, memoranda, opinions, notebooks, and a docket book.
  The cases are arranged by type of case (admiralty, bankruptcy, civil, criminal, or equity cases) and therein alphabetically. Legal notes and court of appeals memoranda are arranged alphabetically. Law school notebooks and legal miscellany are arranged by subject.
  - Admiralty cases (Box 50)
    - "A-F" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - "G-L" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 51)
    - Re "Linseed King", (4 folders)
    - "M-O" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - "P-S" miscellaneous, (8 folders) (Box 52)
    - Stevens v. Columbian Mail S.S.
    - "T-W" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 53)
  - Bankruptcy cases (Box 54)
    - General, (4 folders)
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Burns Bros.
    - "C-D" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - "E-G" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 55)
    - Governor Clinton Hotel, New York, N.Y., (5 folders)
    - "H-I" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 56)
    - McCrory Stores, (3 folders)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Mur-Mo Dress Co.
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "P-V" miscellaneous, (12 folders) (Box 57)
    - "W" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 58)
    - Wil-low Cafeterias
    - Wise Shoe Co., (2 folders)
    - Witherbee Court Corp.
    - "X-Z" miscellaneous
  - Civil cases (Box 59)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Aliens, (3 folders)
    - "B-E" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - "F-K" miscellaneous, (10 folders) (Box 60)
    - "L-N" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 61)
    - New York State Guernsey Breeders Coop. v. Wallace
    - "O-P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Parmley v. Luddum, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 62)
    - "R-S" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - "T-U" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 63)
    - United States v. Renkoff
    - United States v. Weiss, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Criminal cases (Box 65)
    - "A-H" miscellaneous, (15 folders)
    - "I-P" miscellaneous, (13 folders) (Box 66)
    - Prohibition, (9 folders) (Box 67)
    - "Q" miscellaneous
    - "R-U" miscellaneous, (8 folders) (Box 68)
    - United States v. Weiss (Box 69)
    - "V-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Equity cases (Box 70)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Albee v. Perkins, (3 folders)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Brown v. Molie Co.
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - California Fruit Growers Exch. v. Sunkist Drinks
    - Carlston Hoist and Mach. v. Builders Equip. Corp.
    - Collier v. Hudson
    - Cookson v. Marx and Co. (Box 71)
    - Correct Printing Co. v. Rampo River Printing Co., (2 folders)
    - Crites v. Radtke
    - "D" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Dick Co. v. Marr
    - Dunn v. Waterman Co.
    - "E" miscellaneous (Box 72)
    - E.I.S. Mfr. v. Supco Prod.
    - Eureka Prod. v. Lehman
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Fitch v. Shubert
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - General Motors v. Lehr Auto Supply
    - General Production v. Grayson Assoc.
    - Grubb v. General Contracting Purchasing Corp.
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Hallahan v. Schwab and Mandel (Box 73)
    - "I" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Irving Trust Co. v. Conte
    - Isaac Leon Corp. v. Marshall, (2 folders)
    - Isbrandtsen-Moller v. United States, (4 folders)
    - Ishmian S.S. v. United States
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Jetter and Scheerer Products v. Gibbs and Co., (3 folders) (Box 74)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kaunagraph Co. v. Central Trademark
    - Klant v. Deltschaft
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Lewis Invisible Stitch Mach. v. Fourway Knife Pinking Mach.
    - Lisichin v. Miller
    - "M" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 75)
    - Munz v. Harnett
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - National Elec. Prod. v. Grossman
    - "O-P" miscellaneous
    - Prudential Ins. v. Land Estates, (3 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Rewave Heaters v. Nestle-Muir Co.
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Southern Ohio Sav. Bank v. Guarantee Trust Co.
    - Turner Dock Transfer Co. v. Terminal Eng'g
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Ulman v. Sobel
    - United Van Lines v. United Transit Lines
    - United States v. Gordon
    - United States v. Jewell, (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - United States v. Miller, (4 folders)
    - "V-Z" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
  - Legal notes (Box 78)
    - Admiralty
    - Aliens
    - Allowances
    - Assignee as a real party
    - Bankruptcy
      - Amendments of specifications
      - Compositions
      - Extension time
      - Listing debt
      - Proof of claim
      - Rent claims
      - Right to appoint trustee
      - Summary jurisdiction
    - Banks and banking
    - Binders
    - Cancellations and counterclaims
    - Carriers
    - Choses in possession action
    - Collision in fog
    - Compositions in common law
    - Conditional sale
    - Contempt motion
    - Contract requirements
    - Copyrights
    - Corporation stock and bond issues
    - Damages
    - Deceit and frauds
    - Discharges
    - Examinations under 21A
    - Foreclosure suits
    - General averages
    - Impersonations
    - Injunctions
    - Insolvency
    - Insurance
    - Issues of presumption
    - Judicial sales
    - Jurisdictional amounts
    - Leases
    - Liens
    - Limitations of values
    - Miscellaneous, (7 folders); (11 folders); (13 folders); (10 folders) (Box 79, Box 80, Box 81, Box 82)
    - Mortgages (Box 83)
    - Naturalization
    - Negligence
    - Patent infringements
    - Personam
    - Preferences
    - Prohibition
    - Railways
    - Receipts
    - References
    - Removals
    - Seizures
    - Separable controversies
    - Services on foreign corporations
    - Sherman Act
    - Stockholders suits
    - Taxes, (5 folders)
    - Torts
    - Trademarks
    - Transfers
    - Trusts
    - Turnover orders
    - Voidable preferences
    - Workman's compensation
  - Law school notebooks, 1912-1915 (Box 84)
    - Criminal procedure
    - Contracts, (2 vols.)
    - Conflicts of the law (Box 85)
    - Constitutional law
    - Suretyship
    - Bankruptcy (Box 86)
    - Corporations
    - Pleading before the bench (Box 87)
    - Property, (2 folders)
  - United State Circuit Court of Appeals memoranda, 1939-1940 (Box 88)
    - A-L, (12 folders)
    - M-Z, (14 folders) (Box 89)
  - Miscellany (Box 90)
    - Docket book 1939
    - Indexed list of all cases heard by Patterson, 1930-1938
- Speech File, 1940-1951 (Box 91-92)
  Speeches and radio broadcasts.
  Arranged chronologically and indexed. Some of the speeches are bound.
  - Aug. 1940-Sept. 1945, (2 vols.) (Box 91)
  - Jan. 1947-Nov. 1951, (2 vols. and 5 folders) (Box 92)
- Miscellany, 1925-1956 (Box 93-98)
  Reports, a manuscript, notes, correspondence of Margaret Patterson, guest books, a journal, awards, financial statements, year books, biographical material, clippings, appointment books, and a diary.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Reports of the commanding general of the Army Air Forces to the secretary of war, 4 Jan. 1944, 25 Feb. 1945, 12 Nov. 1945 (Box 93)
  - Report by the supreme allied commander, Mediterranean section, to the combined chiefs of staff on the operation in southern France, Aug. 1944
  - Report by the supreme allied commander, Mediterranean section, to the combined chiefs of staff on the Italian campaign, 8 Jan. 1944-10 May 1945
  - Report by the supreme commander to the combined chiefs of staff on the operations in Europe of the allied expeditionary force, 6 June 1944-8 May 1945
  - Typed draft copy, with corrections, of an unpublished manuscript, "Weapons and War," prepared by Henry F. Pringle in 1946 for the secretary of war, (7 folders)
  - Notes and correspondence concerning "Weapons and War," by Henry F. Pringle, 1945-1946 (Box 94)
  - Funeral guest book for persons attending the wake of Patterson, 1952
  - Register of floral tributes to Patterson, 1952
  - Copy of the Congressional Record, 23 Jan. 1952
  - Undated notes on:
    - General John J. Pershing's experiences in World War I.
    - Donald Knudsen Nelson's book, Arsenal of Democracy
    - Company F, 306th Infantry
    - History of the War Department/judicial power
  - Untitled report on various wartime activities in the post World War I period, undated
  - Biennial report of the chief of staff of the U.S. Army to the secretary of war, 1 July 1943-30 June 1945
  - Report on the Industrial Reparations Survey of Japan to the U.S., Feb. 1948 (Box 95)
  - Daily journal of Patterson, 1929
  - Award from Norwich University, Northfield, Vt., Aug. 1944
  - Award from Union College, Schenectady, N.Y.
  - Five-year report on the procurement of munitions by the War Department, Munitions for the Army, Apr. 1946
  - Report on Military Air Transportation Service delivered before the Eberstadt Committee, Oct. 1948
  - Financial statement for the legal firm of Webb, Patterson and Hadley, 1930
  - Annotated copy of the yearbook of the University of Virginia Club, 1930-1931
  - Correspondence of Margaret Patterson, Library of Congress, 1954-1955 (Box 96)
  - Correspondence of Margaret Patterson regarding Robert Porter Patterson's estate, 1952-1956
  - Biographical material
  - Compilation of basic information on the reorganization of the executive branch of the government of the U.S., 1912-1917
  - Diary of Robert Porter Patterson, 1925
  - Harvard Law School Association, (2 folders)
  - Christmas greetings, 1943-1945, (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - Newspaper clippings, (5 folders)
  - Scrapbook, tour of the Pacific, Aug.-Sept. 1943
  - Sketch of Patterson by J. Mathews, undated
  - Appointment books (photocopies), Sept. 1945-July 1947 (Box 98)
- Scrapbooks, 1941-1946 (Box 99-107)
  Clippings and printed matter.
  - General (Box 99)
    - "Work or Fight," 14 Feb. 1945
    - War effort, Sept.-Oct. 1943
    - West Coast press (Box 100)
  - Personal (Box 101)
    - July 1940-Aug. 1941
    - Aug. 1941-1942 (Box 102)
    - Aug. 1942-Mar. 1943 (Box 103)
    - Aug. 1943-July 1944 (Box 104)
    - June 1944 (Box 105)
    - Sept. 1945-Dec. 1946 (Box 106)
- Under Secretary of War Files, 1940-1945 (Box 107-211)
  Subject files.
  Arranged alphabetically by title and chronologically therein, with miscellaneous files, card indices, and abstracts of correspondence located at the end.
  - Ad Hoc Committee (Fiscal and Budgetary Organization) (Box 107)
  - Adjutant general, (3 folders)
  - Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense, (2 folders)
  - Africa, (2 folders)
  - Air Associates, labor strike (Box 108)
  - Air, bombers
  - Air Corps, (2 folders)
  - Aircraft, (2 folders)
  - Aircraft Production Board, meetings
  - Air Forces
    - General, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 109)
    - Material and Service Command
    - Reports, (2 folders)
  - Alaska (Box 110)
  - Allison Engines
  - Aluminum, (9 folders)
  - Amberg, Julius H.
  - American Red Cross Donor Service (Box 111)
  - Ammunition, (2 folders)
  - Annual reports
  - Antitrust, (5 folders)
  - Appointments, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 112)
  - Appropriations, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 113)
  - Army emergency relief, (4 folders)
  - Army ground forces
  - Army Industrial College, Washington, D.C., (1 folder) (Box 114)